The graph of click through rate over time might look something like this.
点击率随时间变化的图表可能与此类似
Now, there are some interesting patterns in this graph.
在这个图表中有一些有趣的图案
You can see both weekly and daily variation as
可以看到 每周和每日变化中
people are more likely to click through either in the evening or on the weekend.
人们都更愿意在晚上或周末点击
But this graph can't help us answer our original question, which is,
但这个图表不能帮助我们回答我们原来的问题
is there a problem with the click tracking?
点击跟踪是否有问题
Like I mentioned, you can't really tell if this is how high the rate actually is
像我曾经提到的 你可能无法真正地判断点击率到底有多高
or if it's being artificially inflated by double clicks being recorded.
或是否是因为双击而膨胀的
The click-through-probability over time might look something like this.
随时间变化的点击概率可能看起来更像这个
It looks pretty similar to the rate.
看起来和点击率很像
And again, it's hard to tell by this graph alone whether there's a problem.
再强调一遍 很难仅通过这个图表判断是否有问题
Now lets take a look at both the rate and the probability on the same graph.
现在我们看看同一图表上的点击率和点击概率
You can see that the rate is consistently higher
可以看到点击率总是比
than the probability.
点击概率高
But that's to be expected whether there's a problem or not and
可以预料到 无论是否有问题
it's hard to know how much higher you would expect the rate to be.
都很难知道你本希望点击率有多高
The difference is also consistent over time, so
差异也随着时间的变化而变化
it's hard to see whether there is a problem.
因此很难看出是否有问题
Now let's take a look at click-through-rate by platform.
现在我们看看不同平台的点击率
Now this graph is pretty suspicious,
现在这个图表很可疑
because it shows the click-through-rate being higher on mobile than on desktop.
因为它显示点击率在移动端比电脑端高
But users will have different behavior on desktop than on mobile so,
但用户在电脑端比移动端有更多不同的行为
it's still not really clear that this is a problem with the JavaScript
因此 还是不确定这是 JavaScript 跟踪的问题
tracking and not just a difference in user behavior.
而不是用户行为的差异
You might think the direction of this is the opposite of what you'd expect.
你可能认为这个的方向与你预期的相反
Like maybe you'd expect that the click-through-rate would be higher on
就像你期待的点击率在电脑端
desktop than mobile.
比在移动端要高
But it can be pretty hard to predict things like that.
但这种事情很难预测
So right now, this graph doesn't really give us enough information to be
因此现在 这个图表不能给我们提供足够多的信息
certain that there's a problem, although it is suspicious.
来确定是否有问题 尽管它很可疑
Now if you plot, click-through-probability by platform,
现在 如果你在不同平台绘制点击概率图
you won't see anything suspicious since,
你不会看到任何可疑的信息 因为
if JavaScript does send a duplicate ping.
如果 JavaScript 确实发送一个复制的 ping
The click-through probability will eliminate that, collapsing it into one.
点击概率会将它消除 将它合并成一个
So here we see that the probability is fairly similar between
因此 在这里我们看到电脑端和移动端
desktop and mobile.
的概率非常相似
Which is maybe what you would have expected.
这可能是你期待的结果
So again, we can't tell whether there was a problem.
因此 我们不能判断是否有问题
Finally, if plot both rate and
最后 如果对不同平台绘制点击率和点击概率图
probability by platform, you can clearly see the problem.
你可以清楚地看到这个问题
The click-through-probability is actually slightly lower on mobile,
移动端的点击概率实际上略低些
but the click-through-rate is significantly higher.
点击率明显更高
You won't necessarily be able to narrow it down to duplicate JavaScript pings at
你不必将它缩小 在这个点复制 JavaScript pings
this point, but
但是
this point's pretty clearly to some sort of instrumentation issue.
这个点在某些测试问题中更清楚
This is a good time to talk to your engineers about what could be
这个适合 你可以跟你的工程师
going wrong.
谈论哪里可能出问题了
So to summarize,
总之
only the final graph really made it crystal clear that there was a problem.
只有最后一个图表能够十分清楚地说明有问题
The click-through-rate by platform looked a little suspicious, but
虽然不同平台的点击率看起来有点可疑
it was hard to draw a conclusion from just that graph on its own.
但很难从这个图表本身得出结论